Norman Kent Papers
Norman Kent Papers
- Correspondence-subject file
  - Meissner, Leo J., 1939; 1947-1959,; undated (Box 14)
  - Meltzer, Arthur, 1959 (Box 14)
  - Menihan, John C., 1938-1943; 1950-1970,; undated (Box 15)
  - Mermin, Mildred, 1957-1958 (Box 15)
  - Merrick, James Kirk, 1946; 1957-1969 (Box 15)
  - Messersmith, Fred, 1959-1970; undated (Box 15)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.), 1942; 1951-1970,; undated (Box 15)
  - Metzl, Ervine, 1956-1964; undated (Box 15)
  - Meyers, Beatrice de Lima, 1935-1944; undated (Box 15)
  - Michel, Joan, 1960; undated (Box 15)
  - Middleton, Sallie E., 1969 (Box 15)
  - Millet, Clarence, 1959 (Box 15)
  - Millier, Arthur, 1956 (Box 15)
  - Mitchell, Glen, 1947 (Box 15)
  - Mochi, Ugo, 1964; 1965 (Box 15)
  - Montclair Art Museum, 1951-1970 (Box 15)
  - Morganthaler, Charles A., 1961-1964 (Box 15)
  - Moskowitz, Ira, 1967 (Box 15)
  - Mueller, Hans A., 1944-1950 (Box 15)
  - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, 1960-1970 (Box 15)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1957-1970 (Box 15)
  - Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.), 1955-1966 (Box 15)
  - N, 4 folders (Box 15)
  - Nash, Ray, 1957-1967 (Box 15)
  - Nason, Thomas W., 1933-1950; undated (Box 15)
  - National Academy of Design, 1942-1970; See also Nichols, Hobart (Box 15)
  - National Arts Club, 1964-1970 (Box 15)
  - National Association of Women Artists, Inc., 1956-1961 (Box 15)
  - National Bank of Geneva, New York, 1937-1969; undated (Box 15)
  - National Cowboy Hall of Fame, 1969 (Box 15)
  - National Gallery of Art (U.S.), 1947; 1956-1970 (Box 16)
  - National Gallery of Canada, 1943-1944; 1960-1964 (Box 16)
  - Neiman, LeRoy, 1960-1961; undated (Box 16)
  - Neufeld, Woldemar, 1956; 1968 (Box 16)
  - New Britain Museum of American Art, 1955-1970; undated (Box 16)
  - New York Public Library, 1926-1958; undated (Box 16)
  - New York Water Color Club, 1938; undated (Box 16)
  - New York World's Fair, 1938-1939 (Box 16)
  - Nichols, Dale, 1960-1964; undated (Box 16)
  - Nichols, Hobart, 1943; undated; See also National Academy of Design (Box 16)
  - Nickerson, Ruth, 1962; 1963 (Box 16)
  - Nielsen, Jon, 1963-1964; undated (Box 16)
  - Noble, John A., 1969 (Box 16)
  - Norfolk Museum, 1957-1969; undated (Box 16)
  - Norris, Ben, 1947 (Box 16)
  - Norton Gallery and School of Art, 1945-1946; 1963 (Box 16)
  - Nye, Vernon, 1961-1969; undated (Box 16)
  - O, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Oakley, Thornton, See Philadelphia Water Color Club
  - Oberhardt, William, 1948; 1955-1958 (Box 16)
  - O'Callahan, Kevin B., 1940 (Box 16)
  - Offutt, T. Scott, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Ogg, Oscar, 1943-1947; undated (Box 16)
  - Ogle, Lucille, See Artists and Writers Guild, Inc.
  - O'Hara, Eliot, undated (Box 16)
  - Old Town Galleries, 1965-1971; undated (Box 16)
  - Ortlieb, Robert, 1963 (Box 16)
  - Osver, Arthur, 1960 (Box 16)
  - P, 6 folders (Box 16, 17)
  - Paradise, Philip, 1969 (Box 17)
  - Parshall, Douglass, 1959-1961; undated (Box 17)
  - Partch, Virgil F., undated (Box 17)
  - Pay, George, 1947; 1956-1961,; undated (Box 17)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1969; undated (Box 17)
  - Peirce, Gerry, 1956; 1969 (Box 17)
  - Pejovic, Vlad, 1965-1967; undated (Box 17)
  - Pellew, John C., 1956-1957; 1969-1970,; undated (Box 17)
  - Perlman, Bernard B., 1962 (Box 17)
  - Perrin, C. Robert, 1959-1965; undated (Box 17)
  - Perry, Raymond, 1956-1958 (Box 17)
  - Pescheret, Leon R., 1948; 1956,; undated (Box 17)
  - Peterdi, Gabor, undated (Box 17)
  - Petersen, Christian, 1958; 1959 (Box 17)
  - Philadelphia Museum College of Art, 1947-1965 (Box 17)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1943-1969 (Box 17)
  - Philadelphia Water Color Club, 1947; 1955-1957 (Box 17)
  - Phillips, Douglas, 1962-1963 (Box 17)
  - Phillips, W. J., 1956 (Box 17)
  - Pike, John, 1952; 1959-1969,; undated (Box 17)
  - Pioneer Museum & Haggin Galleries, 1957-1960 (Box 17)
  - Pittman, Hobson, 1939; 1945 (Box 17)
  - Pitz, Henry C., 1939-1970; undated; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Pleissner, Ogden M., 1948-1968 (Box 17)
  - Pohl, Hugo D., 1958 (Box 17)
  - Poor, Henry V., 1952 (Box 17)
  - Porter, J. Erwin, 1941-1970; undated (Box 17)
  - Prairie Print Makers, 1933-1965; undated (Box 17)
  - Pratt Institute, 1932-1965; undated (Box 17)
  - Princeton University, 1954-1957 (Box 17)
  - Print, 1940-1943 (Box 17)
  - Print Club of Albany, 1953; 1961-1968; See also Schafer, Alice Pauline (Box 17)
  - Print Club of Philadelphia, 1930-1942; 1955 (Box 17)
  - Print Club of Rochester, 1934-1966; undated (Box 17)
  - Print Corner, 1929-1935; 1946 (Box 17)
  - Printing House of Leo Hart, 1931-1932 (Box 18)
  - Prohaska, Ray, 1958; 1960 (Box 18)
  - Pugh, Mabel, 1939 (Box 18)
  - Pullinger, Herbert, 1946 (Box 18)
  - Q, 1 folder (Box 18)
  - Quinn, Noel, 1959-1963; undated (Box 18)
  - Quisgard, Liz Whitney, 1956 (Box 18)
  - R, 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Ransom, Will, 1931-1943 (Box 18)
  - Rath, Hildegard, 1960-1963 (Box 18)
  - Ratta, Cesare, 1934 (Box 18)
  - Ray, Ruth, 1956-1961 (Box 18)
  - The Reader's Digest, 1944-1965; undated (Box 18)
  - Reed, Doel, 1954-1965; undated (Box 18)
  - Reed, Walter, 1965-1969 (Box 18)
  - Reep, Edward, 1955-1960 (Box 18)
  - Refregier, Anton, 1966 (Box 18)
  - Reinhold Publishing Corporation, 1952-1967; undated (Box 18)
  - Reiss, Winold, 1939 (Box 18)
  - Reitzel, Marques E., 1933-1936; 1962-1967,; 1944 (Box 18)
  - Remmey, Paul B., 1957 (Box 18)
  - Reusswig, William, 1955-1959; undated (Box 18)
  - Reynard, Grant, 1947-1968; undated (Box 18)
  - Rice, William S., 1929-1944; undated (Box 18)
  - Richard, Betti, 1966; 1967 (Box 18)
  - Richards, Walter DuBois, 1939; 1957-1958 (Box 18)
  - Richardson, Constance, 1961 (Box 18)
  - Riley, Art, 1961-1965; undated (Box 18)
  - Riley, Ken, 1958 (Box 18)
  - Ripley, A. Lassell, 1955; 1966,; undated (Box 18)
  - Rising, Dorothy Milne, 1956-1959 (Box 18)
  - Robinson, Boardman, 1945 (Box 18)
  - Rochester Institute of Technology, 1928; 1938-1947,; 1952-1969,; undated; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Rochester Memorial Art Gallery, 1928-1962; undated (Box 19)
  - Rochester Public Library, 1932-1955 (Box 19)
  - Rochester Savings Bank, 1966-1967 (Box 19)
  - Rockford College, See Reitzel, Marques E.
  - Rockwell, Norman, 1941-1970; undated (Box 19)
  - Rogers, Bruce, 1942-1943 (Box 19)
  - Rogers, Charles B., 1958-1969; undated (Box 19)
  - Rogoff, Herbert, 1969 (Box 19)
  - Rollins, Carl P., See Yale University Press
  - Rood, John, 1959 (Box 19)
  - Rosenthal, Doris, 1947 (Box 19)
  - Ross, Alex, 1968; undated (Box 19)
  - Rowland, Earl, 1957-1958; See also Pioneer Museum & Haggin Galleries (Box 19)
  - Rudolph, Norman G., 1957 (Box 19)
  - Charles L. Rumrill & Co., Inc., 1941-1942; 1951-1954 (Box 19)
  - Rushmore, Arthur, 1942-1955; undated; See also Harper and Brothers (Box 19)
  - Russin, Robert I., 1955-1963 (Box 19)
  - Ruzicka, Rudolph, 1942-1948; 1956,; 1967-1968 (Box 19)
  - S, 8 folders (Box 19, 20)
  - Safford, Ruth Perkins, 1956-1961 (Box 20)
  - Sahlin, Emil Georg, 1928-1929 (Box 20)
  - Samerjan, George, 1956-1963; undated (Box 20)
  - Sample, Paul, 1955; undated (Box 20)
  - Sandburg, Carl, 1957; outgoing (Box 20)
  - Sandzen, Sven Birger, 1939-1940 (Box 20)
  - Santoro, Joseph L. C., 1961-1970 (Box 20)
  - Saris, Anthony, 1959 (Box 20)
  - Sauer, LeRoy D., 1940-1941 (Box 20)
  - Savage, Eugene Francis, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Sawyer, Helen, See Farnsworth School of Art
  - Schaad, Bentley, 1954-1955 (Box 20)
  - Schafer, Alice Pauline, 1947; 1953-1967 (Box 20)
  - Schiwetz, E. M., 1961 (Box 20)
  - Schlemm, Betty Lou, 1963 (Box 20)
  - Schmeckebier, Laurence, 1955-1970 (Box 20)
  - Schmidt, Harvey, 1959 (Box 20)
  - Schnakenberg, Henry E., 1939 (Box 20)
  - Schnittmann, Sascha S., 1969 (Box 20)
  - Schorre, Charles, 1956-1970; undated (Box 20)
  - Schultheiss, Carl M., 1946 (Box 20)
  - Scriver, Robert, 1962-1964 (Box 20)
  - Seckar, Alvena V., 1957-1963 (Box 20)
  - Sendak, Maurice, 1964 (Box 20)
  - Setterberg, Carl, 1958; 1961 (Box 20)
  - Seward, C. A., 1930-1933; undated (Box 20)
  - Sgouros, Thomas, 1961 (Box 20)
  - Shapiro, Irving, 1958-1968 (Box 20)
  - Shaub, Paul, 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Millard Sheets Designs Incorporated, 1959-1969; undated (Box 20)
  - Shelburne Museum, Inc., 1958-1969; undated (Box 20)
  - Shenton, Edward, 1961 (Box 20)
  - Shields, William S., 1959-1960; undated (Box 21)
  - Shinn, Everett, 1923; 1943-1946,; undated (Box 21)
  - Shonnard, Eugenie F., 1966 (Box 21)
  - Shreveport Art Guild, 1970 (Box 21)
  - Simon, Jewel W., 1961 (Box 21)
  - Simpson, Maxwell Stewart, 1962-1963 (Box 21)
  - Sinel, Jo, 1958-1960 (Box 21)
  - Sinz, Walter A., 1957 (Box 21)
  - Sloan, John, 1947 (Box 21)
  - Sloane, Eric, 1956-1961; undated (Box 21)
  - Smith, Charles, 1939; 1962-1966,; undated (Box 21)
  - Smith, David Loeffler, 1959-1963 (Box 21)
  - Smith, Jacob Getlar, 1951-1957 (Box 21)
  - Smith, Virginia Jeffrey, 1956-1959 (Box 21)
  - Smith, William A., 1957; 1965; See also American Watercolor Society (Box 21)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1942-1943; 1958-1968 (Box 21)
  - Society of American Graphic Artists, Inc., 1953-1959; 1966 (Box 21)
  - Society of Illustrators, 1953; 1962-1964 (Box 21)
  - Society of Western Artists, 1958-1960; 1969-1971,; undated (Box 21)
  - Sorel, Edward, undated (Box 21)
  - Spierer, William McK., 1958 (Box 21)
  - Sprunger, Arthur L., 1940 (Box 21)
  - Stahley, Joseph, 1937 (Box 21)
  - Standard, Paul, 1943-1967 (Box 21)
  - Starin, Arthur N., 1964-1967 (Box 21)
  - Stein, Harve, 1957-1958 (Box 21)
  - Steinberg, Harry, 1960 (Box 21)
  - Stone, Ruth Andress, 1963 (Box 21)
  - Stone, Walter King, 1931-1939; undated (Box 21)
  - Strater, Henry, 1961-1968; undated (Box 21)
  - Straus, Julia Bloch, See Bloch, Julia
  - Stuart, Kenneth, 1944; 1952-1957 (Box 21)
  - Stucki, Margaret E., 1966 (Box 21)
  - Sturdevant, William D., 1958-1970 (Box 21)
  - Sundblom, Haddon H., 1956 (Box 21)
  - Surendorf, Charles, 1940 (Box 21)
  - Sutton, George Miksch, 1936 (Box 21)
  - Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts, See Everson Museum of Art
  - Syracuse University, 1929-1943; 1956-1962,; 1970 (Box 21)
  - Szalay, Lajos, 1961-1962 (Box 21)
  - T, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Taubes, Frederic, 1955-1959; undated (Box 21)
  - Taylor, Barnard, 1960-1965; undated (Box 21)
  - Taylor, Bertha Fanning, 1957-1960 (Box 21)
  - Teague, Donald, 1957-1968; undated (Box 21)
  - Terken, John, 1960; 1966 (Box 21)
  - Thollander, Earl, 1959-1961; 1967 (Box 22)
  - Thompson, Ernest Thorne, 1964 (Box 22)
  - Thompson, Harry E., 1957 (Box 22)
  - Thorne, Thomas Elston, 1938; undated (Box 22)
  - Tillenius, Clarence, 1958-1962 (Box 22)
  - Time, 1946-1969; 1933 (Box 22)
  - Tobias, Abraham Joel, 1956 (Box 22)
  - Toledo Museum of Art, 1959-1967 (Box 22)
  - Topolski, Feliks, 1958-1959 (Box 22)
  - Townsend, Harry, 1940 (Box 22)
  - Trauerman, Margy, 1956 (Box 22)
  - Travis, Olin Herman, 1956; 1965 (Box 22)
  - Treidler, Adolph, 1939; 1969,; undated (Box 22)
  - Trenholm, George F., 1948 (Box 22)
  - Trifon, Harriette, 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Tschacbasov, Nahum, 1955 (Box 22)
  - Turner, Janet, undated (Box 22)
  - Tuttle, Henry Emerson, 1945 (Box 22)
  - U, 1 folder (Box 22)
  - Ulp, Clifford M., 1930; 1938-1956,; undated (Box 22)
  - United States Information Agency, 1955-1969; undated (Box 22)
  - United States Works Progress Administration, See Federal Art Project
  - University of Rochester, 1931-1941; 1960-1961,; undated (Box 22)
  - Unwin, Nora S., 1952-1969 (Box 22)
  - Utz, Thornton, undated (Box 22)
  - V, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Van Hasselt, Tony, 1969-1970 (Box 22)
  - Vogel, Donald S., 1955-1959; 1969 (Box 22)
  - Von der Lancken, F., 1936 (Box 22)
  - Von Neumann, Robert, 1940; 1953-1957 (Box 22)
  - W, 7 folders (Box 22)
  - Walsh, John S., 1960-1963 (Box 23)
  - Ward, Lynd, 1947-1970; undated (Box 23)
  - Warren, Ferdinand, 1958-1961 (Box 23)
  - Warwick, Edward, 1939; 1952 (Box 23)
  - Washburn, Kenneth, 1936-1942 (Box 23)
  - Waters, Herbert, 1954-1962; 1970,; undated (Box 23)
  - Watson, Aldren A., 1945; 1952-1968,; undated (Box 23)
  - Watson, Ernest W., 1927-1969; undated (Box 23)
  - Waugh, Coulton, 1962-1971 (Box 23)
  - Weidenaar, Reynold H., 1956-1965 (Box 23)
  - Weitenkampf, Frank, See New York Public Library
  - Welling, Richard, 1964-1970; undated (Box 23)
  - Wengenroth, Stow, 1943-1956; 1966-1971,; undated (Box 23)
  - Wenrich, John C., 1932-1936; 1946-1968,; undated (Box 23)
  - Werner, Alfred, 1959-1968; undated (Box 23)
  - Weygers, Alexander G., 1964 (Box 23)
  - Whinston, Charlotte, 1956 (Box 23)
  - Whitaker, Frederic, 1951-1970; undated; 3 folders (Box 23)
  - White, Charles W., 1962 (Box 24)
  - White, Doris, 1963 (Box 24)
  - White, Lawrence Grant, See National Academy of Design
  - White, Nelson C., 1958 (Box 24)
  - Whitney, Edgar A., 1956-1961; undated (Box 24)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1956-1968 (Box 24)
  - Who's Who in America, See A. N. Marquis Company
  - Wickey, Harry, 1961-1965 (Box 24)
  - Wickser, Josephine W., 1935-1942 (Box 24)
  - Wilbur, Lawrence Nelson, 1957-1958 (Box 24)
  - Wilcox, Frank N., 1933; 1947,; 1955-1964,; undated (Box 24)
  - Wildenhain, Frans, 1958 (Box 24)
  - Wilford, Loran F., 1939 (Box 24)
  - Wilimovsky, Charles A., 1939 (Box 24)
  - Will, Blanca, 1935; undated (Box 24)
  - Willard, Howard, 1958; 1960 (Box 24)
  - Williams, Esther, 1947 (Box 24)
  - Williams, Mary F., 1938-1943 (Box 24)
  - Williams, Warner, 1966 (Box 24)
  - Williams, Wheeler, 1959 (Box 24)
  - Wilson, Charles Banks, 1969; undated (Box 24)
  - Wilson, Edward A., 1939-1967; undated (Box 24)
  - Winkler, John, undated (Box 24)
  - Winslow, Leon L., 1963-1964 (Box 24)
  - John C. Winston Company, 1955-1957 (Box 24)
  - Winter, Edward, 1946; 1955-1965; 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Winter, Lumen Martin, 1957-1958; 1966-1968 (Box 24)
  - Witherstine, Donald F., 1940 (Box 24)
  - Wood, Beatrice, 1960 (Box 24)
  - Woodbury, David 0., 1964-1967 (Box 24)
  - Woodcut Society, See Fowler, Alfred
  - Woodward, Stanley, 1957; 1962 (Box 24)
  - Worcester Art Museum, 1956-1964 (Box 24)
  - Wright, George H., 1945; 1947 (Box 24)
  - Wyeth, Andrew, 1956; 1965-1968,; undated (Box 24)
  - Y, 1 folder (Box 24)
  - Yale University Press, 1944-1946; 1969 (Box 24)
  - Young, Joseph L., 1956-1961; undated (Box 24)
  - Young, Mahonri M., 1947 (Box 24)
  - Youngblood, Nat, 1957; 1961 (Box 24)
  - Z, 1 folder (Box 24)
  - Zadig, Bertrand, 1939; 1944,; undated (Box 24)
  - Zorach, William, 1939; 1958 (Box 24)
  - Zornes, Milford, 1961-1969 (Box 24)
  - Fragments (Box 24)
  - Unidentified (Box 24)
- Artwork
  - Inventories and lists, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Drawings (5) (Box 25)
  - Prints (11) (Box 25)
  - Unidentified artists (6) (Box 25)
- Writings
  - Essays
    - "Art," The New International Year Book, Events of 1953 (Box 25)
    - "Art and Architecture -- 1952", manuscript (Box 25)
    - "C. B. Falls: A Career in Retrospective," The Players Bulletin, Spring 1962 (Box 25)
    - "Foreword", manuscript (Box 25)
    - "Foreword" 5th Regional Art Exhibition, 1957 (Box 25)
    - Henry Gasser, NA - Introduction, 1968 (Box 25)
    - "Henry Gasser at Grand Central," American Artist Greater New York Section, 1968 (Box 25)
    - "Hudson River Sketching," American Artist Metropolitan, Jan. 1969 (Box 25)
    - "Letter to the Editor," Arts, Apr. 1957 (Box 25)
    - "The Linoleum Cut," The Instructor, June 1932; incomplete (Box 25)
    - "Notes on Morris and His Albion Press", ms. drafts (Box 25)
    - "Portfolio of Drawings of Old Mills," American Artist, Sept. 1967 (Box 25)
    - "The Print Club of Rochester: an Historical Sketch of Its First Ten Years (1931-1940)", ms. draft (Box 25)
    - "The Print Clubs in the United States", ms. draft (Box 25)
    - "Ranulph Bye," Watercolors by Ranulph Bye, 1956 (Box 25)
    - "Rebuttal on How Editors Look at Their Jobs", manuscripts (Box 25)
    - "Reflections," American Artist, June 1968 (Box 25)
    - "Rehberger", ms. draft (photocopy) (Box 25)
    - 'Scrapstracts:' Edward Saxe - Introduction, undated; ms. (Box 25)
    - "Windy Day, Isle of Orleans", manuscript (Box 25)
    - "Wintering in Italy with Norman Kent," Democrat and Chronicle, undated (Box 25)
    - "The Wood Cut Book Plate", manuscripts (Box 25)
    - Untitled - "Perhaps there is ...", manuscript (Box 25)
  - Journal - Scandinavian trip, 1963 (Box 25)
  - Notebook, undated (Box 25)
  - Reviews (by title of work), manuscripts (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 25)
- Memorabilia
  - Award - Art Directors Club, 1955 (Box 25)
  - Calendars, 1920-1936; 2 of 8 folders (Box 25)
  - Calendars, 1937-1967; 5 of 8 folders (Box 26)
  - Calendars, 1968-1970; 1 of 8 folders (Box 27)
  - Calligraphic specimens (Box 27)
  - Financial material
    - General, 1926-1971; 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Royalty statements, 1962-1970 (Box 27)
  - Legal - contracts (Box 27)
  - Photographs (Box 27)
  - Printed material
    - Clippings
      - Articles about, 1936-1970; undated (Box 27)
      - Articles about (peripheral mention), 1946-1969; undated (Box 27)
      - Miscellaneous, 1923-1970; undated (Box 27)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1942-1971; undated (Box 27)
    - Exhibition catalogs
      - Norman Kent (one-man shows), 1941-1967 (Box 28)
      - Norman Kent (group shows), 1931-1970; undated (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous (various artists), 1932-1970; undated (Box 28)
    - Press releases, 1955-1959 (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 28)
  - Publicity, 1963-1970; undated (Box 28)
  - Reviews (excerpts) (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 28)